/*61TKqzUDPHfv40Bqr6iEsqqBCfa360mt*/

var arrayOfQuestionObjects = [{"Question": "Edwin Jarvis serves as butler to what superteam?",
"ChoiceOne": "Teen Titans", "ChoiceTwo": "Fantastic Four", "ChoiceThree": "Justice League", 
"ChoiceFour": "Avengers", "Answer": "Avengers", "GIPHYID": "Avengers"}, 
{"Question": "Who was the first costumed superhero?", "ChoiceOne": "Arrow", "ChoiceTwo": "Crimson Avenger", 
"ChoiceThree": "Superman", "ChoiceFour": "The Phantom", "Answer": "The Phantom", "GIPHYID": "Marvel+Superhero"}, 
{"Question": "Who was the first superhero Spider-Man ever encountered?", "ChoiceOne": "Terrible Tinkerer", 
"ChoiceTwo": "Supercharger", "ChoiceThree": "Doctor Octopus", "ChoiceFour": "Green Goblin", 
"Answer": "Supercharger", "GIPHYID": "Spider-Man"}, 
{"Question": "What super-villain kidnapped and murdered Peter Parker's girlfriend Gwen Stacy?",
"ChoiceOne": "The Rhino", "ChoiceTwo": "Doctor Octopus", "ChoiceThree": "Green Goblin", "ChoiceFour": "Electro", 
"Answer": "Green Goblin", "GIPHYID": "Green+Goblin"}, {"Question": "What did Spider-Man bring home from the first 'Secret Wars'?",
"ChoiceOne": "Alien Flu", "ChoiceTwo": "A Keychain", "ChoiceThree": "New Girlfriend", "ChoiceFour": "New Costume", 
"Answer": "New Costume", "GIPHYID": "Spider-Man"}, {"Question": "What was the name of Peter Parker's uncle?",
"ChoiceOne": "Bruce", "ChoiceTwo": "Ben", "ChoiceThree": "Thomas", "ChoiceFour": "Bob", "Answer": "Ben", 
"GIPHYID": "Uncle+Ben+Spider-Man"}, {"Question": "Who was Peter Parker's first superhuman girlfriend?",
"ChoiceOne": "Ms. Marvel", "ChoiceTwo": "White Tiger", "ChoiceThree": "Kitty Pryde", "ChoiceFour": "Black Cat", 
"Answer": "Black Cat", "GIPHYID": "Spider-Man+Black+Cat"},
{"Question": "What other superhero helped Spider-Man the first time he fought the Ringmaster and his Circus of Crime?",
"ChoiceOne": "Iron Man", "ChoiceTwo": "Human Torch", "ChoiceThree": "Hawkeye", "ChoiceFour": "Daredevil", 
"Answer": "Daredevil", "GIPHYID": "Marvel's+Daredevil"}, {"Question": "Which Spider-Man villain dresses and acts like a 1920s gangster?",
"ChoiceOne": "Mister Negative", "ChoiceTwo": "Finisher", "ChoiceThree": "Big Wheel", "ChoiceFour": "Hammerhead", 
"Answer": "Hammerhead", "GIPHYID": "Al+Capone"}, {"Question": "What is Clark Kent's middle name?",
"ChoiceOne": "Joseph", "ChoiceTwo": "Walter", "ChoiceThree": "Thomas", "ChoiceFour": "Jacob", 
"Answer": "Joseph", "GIPHYID": "Clark+Kent"},
{"Question": "What is the name of the dimensional plane where Kryptonian criminals were exiled?",
"ChoiceOne": "No Man's Land", "ChoiceTwo": "Zimbardo's Prison", "ChoiceThree": "Bizarro World", 
"ChoiceFour": "Phantom Zone", "Answer": "Phantom Zone", "GIPHYID": "Phantom+Zone+Superman"},
{"Question": "Which of Superman's sweethearts became the super-heroine known as Insect Queen?",
"ChoiceOne": "Lana Lang", "ChoiceTwo": "Lois Lane", "ChoiceThree": "Lori Lemaris", "ChoiceFour": "Lyla Lerrol", 
"Answer": "Lana Lang", "GIPHYID": "Lana+Lang+Superman"},
{"Question": "Who did Superman entrust with a Kryptonite ring to stop him if he ever turned evil?",
"ChoiceOne": "Wonder Woman", "ChoiceTwo": "Lois Lane", "ChoiceThree": "Batman", "ChoiceFour": "Jimmy Olsen", 
"Answer": "Batman", "GIPHYID": "Superman+Batman"}, {"Question": "Who created Superman?",
"ChoiceOne": "Jerry Siegel & Stan Lee", "ChoiceTwo": "Joe Shuster & Jerry Siegel", "ChoiceThree": "Jack Kirby & Bob Kane", 
"ChoiceFour": "Bob Kane & Joe Shuster", "Answer": "Joe Shuster & Jerry Siegel", "GIPHYID": "Superman"},
{"Question": "What is Superman's Kryptonian name?", "ChoiceOne": "Jimbo", "ChoiceTwo": "Jor-El", 
"ChoiceThree": "Kal-El", "ChoiceFour": "Zor-El", "Answer": "Kal-El", "GIPHYID": "Krypton+Superman"},
{"Question": "What super-villain once broke Batman's back, leaving him crippled?", "ChoiceOne": "Bane", 
"ChoiceTwo": "Joker", "ChoiceThree": "Killer Croc", "ChoiceFour": "Ra's Al Ghul", "Answer": "Bane", 
"GIPHYID": "Bane"}, {"Question": "Which of these Bat-villains was introduced first?",
"ChoiceOne": "The Riddler", "ChoiceTwo": "Mr. Freeze", "ChoiceThree": "Catwoman", "ChoiceFour": "The Penguin", 
"Answer": "Catwoman", "GIPHYID": "Catwoman"}, {"Question": "Which of the following characters did Bruce Wayne have a son with?",
"ChoiceOne": "Catwoman", "ChoiceTwo": "Vesper Fairchild", "ChoiceThree": "Poison Ivy", "ChoiceFour": "Talia Al Ghul", 
"Answer": "Talia Al Ghul", "GIPHYID": "Talia+Al+Ghul+Batman"},
{"Question": "What superhero team did Batman found with Metamorpho and Black Lightning?", "ChoiceOne": "Crusaders", 
"ChoiceTwo": "All-Star Squadron", "ChoiceThree": "Outsiders", "ChoiceFour": "Batman Incorporated", 
"Answer": "Outsiders", "GIPHYID": "Batman"}, {"Question": "What former DA became the villain known as Two-Face?",
"ChoiceOne": "Jason Blood", "ChoiceTwo": "Edward Nygma", "ChoiceThree": "Harvey Dent", "ChoiceFour": "Floyd Lawton", 
"Answer": "Harvey Dent", "GIPHYID": "Two+Face+Batman"}, {"Question": "What is Captain America's secret identity?",
"ChoiceOne": "Tony Stark", "ChoiceTwo": "Steve Rogers", "ChoiceThree": "Peter Parker", "ChoiceFour": "Clint Barton", 
"Answer": "Steve Rogers", "GIPHYID": "Captain+America"}, {"Question": "Who was Captain America's sidekick during WW2?",
"ChoiceOne": "Miss America", "ChoiceTwo": "Flag Boy", "ChoiceThree": "Union Jack", "ChoiceFour": "Bucky", 
"Answer": "Bucky", "GIPHYID": "Captain+America"}, {"Question": "What was the original shape of Captain America's shield?",
"ChoiceOne": "Star", "ChoiceTwo": "Badge", "ChoiceThree": "Circular", "ChoiceFour": "Square", "Answer": "Badge", 
"GIPHYID": "Captain+America+Shield"}, {"Question": "What is the name of Thor's enchanted hammer?",
"ChoiceOne": "Fenris", "ChoiceTwo": "Gungir", "ChoiceThree": "Mjolnir", "ChoiceFour": "Asgard", 
"Answer": "Mjolnir", "GIPHYID": "Thor+Hammer"}, {"Question": "Who is Thor's father?", "ChoiceOne": "Balder",
"ChoiceTwo": "Fenris", "ChoiceThree": "Loki", "ChoiceFour": "Odin", "Answer": "Odin", "GIPHYID": "Thor"},
{"Question": "What animals pull Thor's chariot?", "ChoiceOne": "Wolves", "ChoiceTwo": "Lions", "ChoiceThree": "Goats", 
"ChoiceFour": "Bulls", "Answer": "Goats", "GIPHYID": "Thor+Chariot"}, {"Question": "What actor plays Thor?",
"ChoiceOne": "Mark Ruffalo", "ChoiceTwo": "Chris Hemsworth", "ChoiceThree": "Chris Evans", 
"ChoiceFour": "Jeremy Renner", "Answer": "Chris Hemsworth", "GIPHYID": "Chris+Hemsworth"},
{"Question": "Which of Thor's enemies was a child of Loki?", "ChoiceOne": "Ymir", "ChoiceTwo": "Fenris Wolf", 
"ChoiceThree": "Lorelei", "ChoiceFour": "Mephisto", "Answer": "Fenris Wolf", "GIPHYID": "Loki"},
{"Question": "Which of Wonder Woman's accessories was forged from the magic girdle of Aphrodite?",
"ChoiceOne": "Her lasso", "ChoiceTwo": "Her bracelets", "ChoiceThree": "Her tiara", "ChoiceFour": "Her earrings", 
"Answer": "Her lasso", "GIPHYID": "Wonder+Woman+lasso"},
{"Question": "Which of Wonder Woman's accessories allows her to breathe in outer space?",
"ChoiceOne": "Her lasso", "ChoiceTwo": "Her bracelets", "ChoiceThree": "Her tiara", "ChoiceFour": "Her earrings", 
"Answer": "Her earrings", "GIPHYID": "Wonder+Woman"}, {"Question": "Who was the first villain Wolverine encountered?",
"ChoiceOne": "Wendigo", "ChoiceTwo": "Lady Deathstrike", "ChoiceThree": "Sabretooth", "ChoiceFour": "Silver Samurai", 
"Answer": "Wendigo", "GIPHYID": "Wolverine"}, {"Question": "What is the name of the metal that lines Wolverine's skeleton?",
"ChoiceOne": "Vibrabium", "ChoiceTwo": "Lead", "ChoiceThree": "Adamantium", "ChoiceFour": "Steel", 
"Answer": "Adamantium", "GIPHYID": "Logan Claws"},
{"Question": "Magneto did something to Wolverine that would have killed anyone else. What did he do?",
"ChoiceOne": "Put him in a metal box and crushed it", "ChoiceTwo": "Sent him through a saw mill", 
"ChoiceThree": "Ripped out his skeleton", "ChoiceFour": "Crushed him with a dump truck", 
"Answer": "Ripped out his skeleton", "GIPHYID": "Magneto+Xmen"}, {"Question": "What is Magneto's full name?",
"ChoiceOne": "Erik Luther Xavier", "ChoiceTwo": "Erik Charles Housten", "ChoiceThree": "Erik Magnus Lehnsherr", 
"ChoiceFour": "Erik Jones Luther", "Answer": "Erik Magnus Lehnsherr", "GIPHYID": "Magneto+Xmen"},
{"Question": "What do the scars on Nightcrawler's body represent?", "ChoiceOne": "Every crime he has committed",
"ChoiceTwo": "Every time he has sinned", "ChoiceThree": "Every person he has killed", 
"ChoiceFour": "Every time he has stolen", "Answer": "Every time he has sinned", "GIPHYID": "Nightcrawler+Xmen"},
{"Question": "The original Green Lantern was part of what superhero team?", "ChoiceOne": "Green Lantern Corps",
"ChoiceTwo": "Justice Society of America", "ChoiceThree": "Seven Soldiers of Victory", 
"ChoiceFour": "Justice League of America", "Answer": "Justice Society of America", "GIPHYID": "Green+Lantern"},
{"Question": "Who gave Hal Jordan his power ring?", "ChoiceOne": "An Egyptian ghost", "ChoiceTwo": "A dying alien", 
"ChoiceThree": "Superman", "ChoiceFour": "His father", "Answer": "A dying alien", "GIPHYID": "Green+Lantern+Ring"},
{"Question": "What was Hal Jordan's job before he became Green Lantern?", "ChoiceOne": "Social worker",
"ChoiceTwo": "Test pilot", "ChoiceThree": "Police officer", "ChoiceFour": "Petty criminal", 
"Answer": "Test pilot", "GIPHYID": "Green+Lantern"},
{"Question": "Who was the long-time nemesis/love interest of the Silver Age Green Lantern",
"ChoiceOne": "Zatanna", "ChoiceTwo": "Bella Donna", "ChoiceThree": "Star Sapphire", "ChoiceFour": "Black Mamba", 
"Answer": "Star Sapphire", "GIPHYID": "Silver+Age+Green+Lantern"},
{"Question": "What former Green Lantern member was honorably discharged for abusing his power?",
"ChoiceOne": "Doctor Polaris", "ChoiceTwo": "Sinestro", "ChoiceThree": "Vandal Savage", "ChoiceFour": "Myrwhydden", 
"Answer": "Sinestro", "GIPHYID": "Green+Lantern"}, {"Question": "What was the first superhero team Wonder Woman ever joined?",
"ChoiceOne": "All Star squadron", "ChoiceTwo": "Justice Society of America", "ChoiceThree": "Justice League of America", 
"ChoiceFour": "Doom Patrol", "Answer": "Justice Society of America", "GIPHYID": "Wonder+Woman"}];

var arrayOfQuotes = ['"With great power comes great responsibility" -Uncle Ben', '"Why so serious?" -The Joker',
'"That' + "'" + 's my secret Captain. I' + "'" + 'm always angry!" -Hulk', '"It' + "'" + 's not who I am underneath, but what I do that defines me." -Bruce Wayne',
'"There is a right and wrong in the Universe. And the distinction is not hard to make." -Superman', 
'"Cats come when they feel like, not when they' + "'" + 're told." -Catwoman', '"Some men aren' + "'" + 't looking for something logical like money. They can' + "'" + 't be bought, bullied, reasoned or negotiated with. Some men just want to watch the world burn." -Alfred',
'"No matter how bad things get, something good is out there, just over the horizon." -Green Lantern', 
'"It doesn' + "'" + 't matter who we are. What matters is our plan." -Bane', '"Just because someone stumbles and loses their path, doesn' + "'" + 't mean they can' + "'" + 't be saved." -Professor X',
'"There are no heroes. No villains. Just people with different agendas." -Daredevil',
'"If you could make God bleed, people would cease to believe in him." -Ivan Vanko', '"The answers you seek shall be yours, once I claim what is mine." -Thor',
'"I don' + "'" + 't like bullies. I don' + "'" + 't care where they' + "'" + 're from." -Captain America', '"If you cage the beast, the beast will get angry." -Wolverine',
'"Freedom is life' + "'" + 's great lie. Once you accept that in your heart, you will know peace." -Loki',
'"I should not be alive, unless it was for a reason. I know what I have to do, and I know it is right." -Iron Man',
'"Life does not give us purpose. We give life purpose." -The Flash', 
'"The strength of this country is not in buildings of bricks and steel. It is in the hearts of those who have sworn to fight for its freedom." -Captain America',
'"You are much stronger than you think you are. Trust me." -Superman', '"In a world of ordinary mortals, you are a wonder woman." -Queen Hippolyte',
'"You only have your thoughts and dreams ahead of you. You are someone. You mean something." -Batman',
'"When you decide not to be afraid, you can find friends in super unexpected places." -Ms. Marvel'];

var correct = 0;
var wrong = 0;
var unanswered = 0;
var questionsAsked = 0;
var questionsToAnswer = 10;
var timeToAnswer = 25;
var gifLimit = 5;
var resultScreenShow = 5;
var tickerLock = 1;

function replaceOpeningScreen(){
	$("#opening-screen").addClass("hidden");
	$("#question-screen").removeClass("hidden");
}

function shuffleArray(arr){
	for(var i = 1; i < arr.length; i++) {
		var random = Math.floor(Math.random() * (i + 1));
		if(random !== i) {
			var dummy = arr[random];
			arr[random] = arr[i];
			arr[i] = dummy;
		}
	}
	return arr;
}

function populateQA(){
	questionsAsked++;
	if(questionsAsked <= questionsToAnswer) {
		$("#time").text(timeToAnswer);
		tickerLock = 0;
		var arrayOfChoices = [arrayOfQuestionObjects[questionsAsked].ChoiceOne, 
		arrayOfQuestionObjects[questionsAsked].ChoiceTwo, arrayOfQuestionObjects[questionsAsked].ChoiceThree,
		arrayOfQuestionObjects[questionsAsked].ChoiceFour];
		arrayOfChoices = shuffleArray(arrayOfChoices);
		$("#question").text(arrayOfQuestionObjects[questionsAsked].Question);
		$("#choice-a").text(arrayOfChoices[0]);
		$("#choice-b").text(arrayOfChoices[1]);
		$("#choice-c").text(arrayOfChoices[2]);
		$("#choice-d").text(arrayOfChoices[3]);
		parseAnswer();
	}
	else {
		$("#result-screen").addClass("hidden");
		$("#final-statistics").removeClass("hidden");
		if(correct >= 7)
			$("#verdict").text("You are a bona fide comic book nerd!");
		else if(correct <= 3)
			$("#verdict").text("Well, at least you have a life.")
		else
			$("#verdict").text("You have a healthy knowledge of comics.");
		$("#correct-tally").text(correct);
		$("#wrong-tally").text(wrong);
		$("#unanswered-tally").text(unanswered);
		$(document).on("click", function(){
			$(document).unbind("click");
			correct = 0;
			wrong = 0;
			unanswered = 0;
			questionsAsked = 0;
			arrayOfQuestionObjects = shuffleArray(arrayOfQuestionObjects);
			arrayOfQuotes = shuffleArray(arrayOfQuotes);
			$("#final-statistics").addClass("hidden");
			$("#question-screen").removeClass("hidden");
			populateQA();
		});
	}
}

function countdown(){
	if(tickerLock != 1) {
		timeToAnswer--;
		$("#time").text(timeToAnswer);
		if(timeToAnswer === 0) {
			timeToAnswer = 25;
			tickerLock = 1;
			openTimeUpScreen();
		}
	}
}

function parseAnswer(){
	$(".answer-container").on("click", function() {
		$(".answer-container").unbind("click");
		tickerLock = 1;
		timeToAnswer = 25;
		var userChoice = $(this).attr("choice");
		$("#question-screen").addClass("hidden");
		$("#result-screen").removeClass("hidden")
		if($("#choice-" + userChoice).text() === arrayOfQuestionObjects[questionsAsked].Answer) {
			$("#result").text("Correct!");
			$("#correct-answer").text(arrayOfQuotes[questionsAsked]);
			correct++;
		}
		else {
			$("#result").text("Wrong!");
			$("#correct-answer").text("Correct answer: " + arrayOfQuestionObjects[questionsAsked].Answer);
			wrong++;
		}
		embedGIF();
		setTimeout(function(){
			if(questionsAsked < questionsToAnswer) {
				$("#result-screen").addClass("hidden");
				$("#question-screen").removeClass("hidden");
			}
			populateQA();}, 1000*resultScreenShow);
	});
}

function embedGIF(){
	$.ajax({
		url: "http://api.giphy.com/v1/gifs/search?q=" + arrayOfQuestionObjects[questionsAsked].GIPHYID
		+ "&api_key=61TKqzUDPHfv40Bqr6iEsqqBCfa360mt&limit=" + gifLimit,
		method: "GET"
	}).then(function(response) {
		var random = Math.floor(Math.random()*gifLimit);
		while(response.data[random].embed_url === "")
			random = Math.floor(Math.random()*gifLimit);
		var gifSelection = response.data[random];
		$("#gif").html("<iframe src='" + gifSelection.embed_url + "' width='" + gifSelection.images["480w_still"]["width"] +
			"' height='" + gifSelection.images["480w_still"]["height"] + "' alt='" + arrayOfQuestionObjects[questionsAsked].GIPHYID + 
			"'>");
	});
}

function openTimeUpScreen(){
	$(".answer-container").unbind("click");
	$("#question-screen").addClass("hidden");
	$("#result-screen").removeClass("hidden");
	$("#result").text("Time's Up!");
	$("#correct-answer").text("Correct answer: " + arrayOfQuestionObjects[questionsAsked].Answer);
	embedGIF();
	unanswered++;
	setTimeout(function(){
		if(questionsAsked < questionsToAnswer) {
			$("#result-screen").addClass("hidden");
			$("#question-screen").removeClass("hidden");
		}
		populateQA();}, 1000*resultScreenShow);
}

$(document).ready(function(){
	$(document).on("click", function(){
		$(document).unbind("click");
		arrayOfQuestionObjects = shuffleArray(arrayOfQuestionObjects);
		arrayOfQuotes = shuffleArray(arrayOfQuotes);
		replaceOpeningScreen();
		setInterval(countdown, 1000);
		populateQA();
	});
});